Walter Stark

Quality Inspector

Barrington, NH - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Walter-Stark/e220637c7af66336

I am looking for a position focusing on, but not limited to, quality control, production control, and/or logistics. I developed an interest in limiting variation within a product, supply chain management, and troubleshooting causation in defects while taking college courses. My work experience, thus far (five years), has allowed me to implement these studies and help solidify my professional trajectory in manufacturing. I am eager to find employment that I enjoy and gain experience.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Quality Inspector

SIG SAUER, Inc. - Exeter, NH - July 2016 to Present

- * Incoming Inspection construct methods that will determine whether supplier parts pass/fail to visual, dimensional, and/or functional standards, document results, and communicate with engineers/supervisors for writing suppliers up for non conformance
- * Outside Process (OSP) verify that visual standards are met prior to deliveries
- * Roving Inspection responsible for completing required random inspections per machine, document results and corrective actions to assure dimensional accuracy, confirm correct prints and paperwork is provided to machinists, verify setups before mass production, verify first articles for new product,
- * Training lead new employees through the importance of quality, teach the basics of GD&T (datum, cross sectional views, call outs,), and demonstrate the usage of equipment (listed under "Professional Skills")
- * ERP (Oracle) update workorder/part location upon completion of operation
- * Equipment Zeiss CMM, Equator, Optical Comparator, Microhite, Micrometer, Profilometer, Indicator, St. Mary's, Caliper, Thread/Ring/Plug Gage, Bore Scope, and Air Gage

Regional NC - Programmer

O'Neal Steel Company - Birmingham, AL - October 2014 to September 2015

- * Interim Supervisor advise forecasting, lead-times, and other processing questions
- * Programming draw, design, and/or nest parts for CNC machines
- * Quoting provide cutting information to salesperson (KERF, cutting speed)
- * Processing machine routing, order completion, and program troubleshooting
- * Inventory plate allocation, plate reclassification, weight change, heat number validation, and inventory audit
- * Continuous Improvement plan and implement Lean Mfg and 5S ideology
- * Miscellaneous Support Function advise product status, expedite orders, research variance issues, and scheduling

Metro PSC Store Manager

Xcell Communications - Birmingham, AL - April 2014 to October 2014

- * Sales responsible for obtaining sale-goals
- * Open and Close responsible for opening and closing my location
- * Accounting separate, document, and secure the daily revenue
- * Inventory order, distribute, and stock
- * Customer Service troubleshooting handsets
- * Audit perform 1st party audits for inventory (weekly)

Marine Toxicology Laboratory Assistant

University of Alabama at Birmingham Biology Department - Birmingham, AL - May 2012 to August 2012

- * Assistant preformed subsample protocol, analyzed, and recorded enzyme clusters
- * Microscope Technician documented images
- * Histologist created slides

Engineering Intern

Kennametal - Irondale, AL - May 2010 to January 2012

- * Miscellaneous Support Function aided machine and fabrication shops
- * Maintenance aided the installation of an air purifier system, conduit, and motors
- * Sales converted physical archives to digital database
- * Safety led a safety analysis for all machines to determine if/which should be replaced
- * Machining read, interpreted, and executed engineering drawings with drill press

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Industrial and Systems Engineering

Mississippi State University - Starkville, MS December 2013

High School Diploma

Alabama School of Mathematics and Science - Mobile, AL May 2009

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Professional Skills

- * Zeiss CMM Intermediate
- * Equator Intermediate
- * Optical Comparator, Microhite, Micrometer, Profilometer, Indicator, St. Mary's, Caliper, Thread/Ring/Plug Gage, Bore Scope, and Air Gage Advanced
- * Microsoft Office (Outlook, Excel, Word, PowerPoint) Advanced
- * SigmaNEST Advanced
- * AutoCAD Advanced
- * JD Edwards ERP Systems Advanced
- * SolidWorks Intermediate
- * FlexSim Simulation Software (Visual Basic and C++) Intermediate
- * Minitab 16 Advanced
- * Linux Intermediate